Preliminary Guide to the Julie LaValle Jones Papers, 1970-1998 RL.00647
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Julie LaValle Jones papers
1970-1998
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Jones, Julie LaValle
RL.00647
4.8 Linear Feet
Julie LaValle Jones was a feminist who worked to prevent domestic violence in the Washington, D.C. area. Accession (2008-0029) (3600 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 1970-1998, bulk 1973-1982) includes speeches, essays, pamphlets and other feminist publications (e.g. newspapers and journals), administrative files of all the feminist organizations Jones founded or worked with, conference files, project files, subject files, correspondence, and ephemera (including four posters and two audiocassettes). Some of the organizations represented include the YWCA, My Sister's Place, the Women's Legal Defense Fund's Task Force on Abused Women, and the Feminist Alliance Against Rape. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
3600 items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Gift, 2008 (2008-0029), 4.8 lin. ft.
Biographical / Historical Note
Julie LaValle Jones was a feminist who worked to prevent domestic violence in the Washington, D.C. area.
Collection Overview
Accession (2008-0029) (3600 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 1970-1998, bulk 1973-1982) includes speeches, essays, pamphlets and other feminist publications (e.g. newspapers and journals), administrative files of all the feminist organizations Jones founded or worked with, conference files, project files, subject files, correspondence, and ephemera (including posters and audiocassettes). Some of the organizations represented include the YWCA, My Sister's Place, the Women's Legal Defense Fund's Task Force on Abused Women, and the Feminist Alliance Against Rape. Acquired as part of the Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture.
Audiocassettes; Rape; Feminism; Family Violence; Washington (D.C.); Feminist Alliance Against Rape (U.S.); Jones, Julie LaValle; Jones, Julie LaValle; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture; Women's Legal Defense Fund, Inc.. -- My Sister's Place; Young Women's Christian Association District of Columbia Branch; Women's Legal Defense Fund, Inc.
- Accession (2008-0029), 8 boxes, 2 oversize folders
  Scope and Contents note
  Accession (2008-0029) (3600 items; 4.8 lin. ft.; dated 1970-1998, bulk 1973-1982) includes speeches, essays, pamphlets and other feminist publications (e.g. newspapers and journals), administrative files of all the feminist organizations Jones founded or worked with, conference files, project files, subject files, correspondence, and ephemera (including four posters and two audiocassettes). Some of the organizations represented include the YWCA, My Sister's Place, the Women's Legal Defense Fund's Task Force on Abused Women, and the Feminist Alliance Against Rape.
  - Printed materials and conference programs, 1970s (Box 1)
    Relating to Jones' work with battered women and wives.
  - Chiswick Women's Aid, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Clippings, 1970s (Box 1)
  - Printed materials, support letters, and proposals, 1970s (Box 2)
  - Spectra Feminist Media Project, 1975 (Box 2)
  - D.C. Feminist Alliance, 1970s (Box 2)
  - D.C. Coalition for the Appointment of Women, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Political Prisoners, 1975 (Box 2)
  - Pornography, 1978 (Box 2)
  - Printed Political Info, 1976 (Box 2)
  - General literature (Box 2)
  - Violence Against Women Taskforce (Box 3)
  - Task Force on Abused Women: My Sister's Place manual of policies and procedures, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Task Force on Abused Women binder of notes, correspondence, pamphlets, 1970s (Box 3)
  - National Coalition Against Domestic Violence, 1980 (Box 3)
  - Clippings, 1980s (Box 3)
  - Originals, 1970s (Box 3)
    Task Force on Abused Women handouts and clippings.
  - Federal agencies, 1970s (Box 3)
  - Center for Women Policy Studies (Box 3)
  - Information from other groups and organizations, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
  - Conference reports, 1976 (Box 4)
  - My Sister's Place publications, 1978-1981 (Box 4)
  - Response newsletter, 1976-1980 (Box 4)
  - International Women's Year, 1977 (Box 4)
  - My Sister's Place materials, 1970s-1980s (Box 4)
  - YWCA, 1980s (Box 4)
  - Feminist organizations publications, 1970s (Box 4)
  - Daybooks, 1972-1980 (Box 5)
    Personal calendars.
  - CETA binder (Task Force on Abused Women materials), 1977 (Box 5)
  - My Sister's Place, 1980 (Box 5)
    Bulletins, notes, minutes, and materials.
  - Women's Legal Defense Fund articles and bylaws (Box 5)
  - Women's Legal Defense Fund materials, 1981 (Box 6)
    My Sister's Place materials, audits, publicity.
  - Feminist Alliance Against Rape, 1978-1979 (Box 6)
  - Articles about domestic violence, 1975-1985 (Box 6)
  - Research notes (Box 6)
  - The Women's Show, radio (WRGW) materials, Feb. 27, 1972 (Box 6)
  - George Washington University Hatchet issues, 1972 (Box 6)
    Covering instances of domestic violence and rape.
  - George Washington University materials, 1970s (Box 6)
  - Books (Box 7)
    - Sassafrass, by Ntozake Shange (Box 7)
    - Roles Women Play: Readings Toward Women's Liberation (Box 7)
    - In Her Day, by Rita Mae Brown (Box 7)
  - Journals and newsletters
    - Quest: feminist quarterly, 1974-1981 (Box 7)
    - Task Force on Abused Women newsletter, Vol. 1.1 (Box 7)
    - National Communication Network for the Elimination of Violence Against Women, Vol. 1.1-1.4, 1977 (Box 7)
    - Feminist Alliance Against Rape (later Aegis), 1976-1982 (Box 7)
    - Amazon Quarterly, Vol. 3.2, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Prostitution (Box 8)
  - Feminist Economic Conference (Box 8)
  - Gay Rights, 1970s (Box 8)
  - Women's Action Alliance (Box 8)
  - Women in Prison, 1973-1977 (Box 8)
  - Domest Relations project (Box 8)
  - My Sister's Place annual report, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Racism (Box 8)
  - Sexual harassment, 1982-1989 (Box 8)
  - Rape, 1970s (Box 8)
  - Quest: communication and control, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Child birth, 1978-1980 (Box 8)
  - Children and childcare, 1976 (Box 8)
  - Health, 1975-1976 and no date (Box 8)
  - Cassette tapes from the Feminist Radio Network
    - Prostitution (Box 8)
    - Ain't it a Shame (Battered Women) (Box 8)
  - Ephemera: feminist buttons, rubber stamp (Box 8)
  - Poster: Up From Under - Free Our Sisters Now, Mt. Holyoke, 1969-1970 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Poster: Disarm Rapists - Smash Sexism (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Poster: March Again for Equal Rights (D.C.) in honor of Alice Paul (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Poster: Wise Women, Strong Proud Healers, Midwives, Creators, and Builders... (Women's Graphics Collective), 1973 (Oversize-folder 1)